# ANDREW CRAIG Front End Web Developer

## **ABOUT:**

Hello, my name is Andrew, I'm an entrepreneur turned Front End Web Developer. I'm passionate about workflow efficiency (Emmet, SCSS and React) and I am excited to write code that saves time for other people. Along with my tech skills, I have nine years of sales experience working with the management of sixteen retail stores in Toronto. My time working as a film director gave me the opportunity to lead teams of five to seventeen people, employing creative solutions to stay within budget and stay on task. I believe my diverse skill set makes me an excellent candidate, and I would love to be a part of your team!

- (416) 826-4854
- andrewcraigweb@gmail.com
- andrewcraigweb.com
- in linkedin.com/in/andrewcraigweb
- Toronto, ON

## **EDUCATION:**

### Front End Web Development • 2021 Juno School of Technology, Toronto, ON

- Web Development Immersive
- Web Dev Fundamentals
- Javascript Fundamentals

Bachelor of Fine Arts • 2002 Concordia University, Montreal, QC

# **SKILLS:**

- HTML 5
- Accessibility
- CSS/SCSS
- Responsive Design
- Javascript
- Team work
- React
- Scheduling
- REST API
- Management
- Firebase
- JQUFRY
- Sales

## **PROJECTS:**

#### Trivia Time

React - SCSS/HTML

### NBACodeStars

Javascript - SCSS/HTML

#### CageFinder

Javascript - CSS/HTML

#### Refrigeration Versification

React - API - Firebase - CSS/HTML

### Oscar Finder

React - Firebase - CSS/HTML

## **EXPERIENCE:**

#### Film Director • 2016 - 2019

#### Red Rabbit Productions, Toronto

- Implemented money saving concepts to achieve best results for low budgets (up to \$22,000)
- Developed detailed action plans, schedules and contingencies for filming on location
- Directed up to 17 cast and crew

#### Product Sales • 2008 - 2020

#### New Roots Herbal, Toronto

- Maintained working relationships with the management and staff of 19 health food stores across the GTA
- Memorized details of over 80 products and explained them to customers in detail while achieving sales quotas

#### Manager • 2006 - 2019

#### Artist Manager, Toronto

- Managed schedules, rehearsals, finances, tour dates and music videos
- Obtained excellent experience in branding, marketing and social media
- Helped negotiate record deals with three different labels
- Built a rapport and working relationships with hundreds of industry professionals and artists

## **AWARDS & RECOGNITION:**

2016 Toronto Independent Music Award nomination for

outstanding music video direction

Signed to WAX/UNIVERSAL record label 2010 - 2013

2011 Winner of Indie Week

2009 Front page interview in the Toronto Star for performance

in Brad Fraser's True Love Lies

2005 Dora award nomination for outstanding performance